Finding Aid for the Carey McWilliams Papers LSC.1319
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 2. Correspondence and research files, 1896-1982; 38 boxes
  - 2A. Files on people, 1912-1982; 11 boxes
    This subseries contains McWilliams's extensive research and correspondence files relating to specific individuals with whom he corresponded, or who were research subjects for his writings. The files contain correspondence (by or about the person named on the file), clippings, ephemera, and assorted printed materials. Arranged alphabetically by surname.
    - Aickman, Duncan, 1947; 9 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      1 letter from Aickman, and typewritten poetry manuscripts.
    - Algren, Nelson, 1953, 1959-1961; 16 items. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with Algren, and a clipping.
    - Alinsky, Saul, 1952-1953, 1971-1972; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      1 letter from Alinsky, clippings, and a newsletter.
    - Austin, Mary (1 of 2), 1934-1938, 1951, 1967-1977; 21 items. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Letters regarding Austin and McWilliams's writings on her; 2 clippings.
    - Austin, Mary (2 of 2), 1927-1934; ca. 130 items. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Photocopied correspondence with Austin from the Carey McWilliams's Collection of Materials About Mary Hunter Austin (Collection 278) and from the Huntington Library. Clippings.
    - Bain, Terry, 1971-1973; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with Bain, and an essay by Bain.
    - Banks, R., 1959; 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Letters from Banks.
    - Beals, Carleton, 1979; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 8)
      1 letter from John A. Britton, and a paper by Britton.
    - Bentley, Eric, 1963, 1969; 5 items. (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Correspondence with Bentley.
    - Berman, Louise, 1955-1956, 1963-1972; 56 items. (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Correspondence (primarily with Berman), a handwritten note, a booklet, a manuscript by McWilliams entitled "Remembering Louise Berman," an invitation to her memorial, and an obituary.
    - Bioff, Willie and the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (1 of 2), 1939-1967; 14 items. (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Letters, 2 manuscripts ("Congress goes to Hollywood" by Bernard J. McMahon and "Hollywood labor dispute--a study in immorality" by George H. Dunne), and newspaper clippings.
    - Bioff, Willie and the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (2 of 2), 1949-1950; 9 items. (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Legal documents, such as transcripts, stipulations, and an opening statement, primarily from the case of Conference of Studio Unions vs. Loew's Incorporated.
    - Botkin, B.A., 1930-1933, 1975; 23 items. (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Letters from Botkin. Also includes a leaflet, a clipping, bibliographies compiled by Botkin and typed reviews of the publication Folk-Say.
    - Boyd, Andrew, 1969-1970, 1979; 48 items. (Box 7, Folder 14)
      Correspondence with Boyd, typed notes, and manuscripts by Boyd.
    - Boyle, Kay, 1970-1971; 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 15)
      Correspondence with Boyle.
    - Bradbury, Ray, 1952-1953, 1960; 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with Bradbury.
    - Bronowski, Jacob (1 of 2), 1957-1976; 23 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Letters regarding Bronowski's work, correspondence between Bronowski and McWilliams, typed notes, and four manuscripts (1 untitled by McWilliams, "Bronowski: Man of Many Gifts" by McWilliams, "Sociological Knowledge and Social Control" by Robert Bierstedt, and "A Tribute to J. Bronowski" by Gerard Piel).
    - Bronowski, Jacob (2 of 2), 1958-1975; ca. 30 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Articles and clippings, including published works by McWilliams about Bronowski.
    - Brown, Jerry, 1974-1979; ca. 50 items. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Correspondence with Brown, one press release, and clippings.
    - Bunker, Eddie, 1972, 1976-1979; 29 items. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with Bunker (as well as letters regarding Bunker), a book jacket, an article by Bunker, and clippings.
    - Burgess, Larry E., 1979; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      1 letter from Burgess, and brochures on the A.K. Smiley Public Library and the Lincoln Memorial Shrine.
    - Burke, Kenneth, 1959-1969; 14 items. (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Correspondence with Burke, clippings, and an annotated poem and a manuscript by Burke.
    - Cain, James M., 1933, 1969, 1977; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      One letter from Cain, and clippings.
    - Carlson, Colonel Evans F., 1945, 1970; 5 items. (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Handwritten note from Alex Pesonen, an address by Carlson, and clippings of McWilliams's articles.
    - Carney, Francis, 1977-1979; 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Correspondence with Carney.
    - Carr, Harry, 1931, 1975; 6 items. (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Letters (mostly from Carr to McWilliams), and a clipping.
    - Carrington, Otis M., 1934; 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Correspondence with Carrington about his brother's letters from Ambrose Bierce.
    - Chandler, Raymond, 1973-1976; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Clippings, including an article written by Chandler.
    - Chavez, Cesar, 1970-1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Correspondence with Chavez, a press release, a leaflet, and newspaper clippings. Also includes a quote from Chavez about Factories in the Field. These materials mostly refer to Chavez in context as the leader of the United Farm Workers.
    - Chevalier, Haakon, 1954-1967; 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Correspondence with Chevalier regarding an open letter from Chevalier to J. Robert Oppenheimer that was to appear in The Nation. Also includes correspondence between Philip M. Stern and McWilliams, and newspaper clippings.
    - Chotiner, Murray, 1960-1966; 12 items. (Box 8, Folder 16)
      One letter regarding Chotiner, a typed note, clippings, and assorted printed materials.
    - Clark, Evans, 1951; 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 17)
      Correspondence with Clark, and a clipping.
    - Cobb, Humphrey, 1939-1978; 29 items. (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Correspondence (primarily with Cobb), along with some assorted printed materials, including a black and white photograph.
    - Collins, Seward, 1930-1931; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 19)
      Correspondence with Collins.
    - Condon, Richard, 1962-1964; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 20)
      Correspondence with Condon.
    - Conover, Grandin, 1969-1971; 6 items. (Box 8, Folder 21)
      Letters regarding Conover, one letter from Conover to McWilliams, and photocopies of Conover's work.
    - Cooper, Evelyn N., 1951-1953; 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with Cooper.
    - Couch, William Jr., 1966-1970; 10 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with Couch.
    - Cowell, Henry, 1939-1965; 45 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Letters, primarily from Olive Thompson Cowell, and clippings. Also contains correspondence with the prison board and a few letters from McWilliams to Henry Cowell.
    - Crane, Clarkson, 1928-1931, 1961-1975; 19 items. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Photocopies of letters, primarily from Crane to McWilliams.
    - Curtis, Christine Turner, 1931-1935; 7 items. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Letters from Curtis.
    - Daggett, Charles, 1951; 4 items. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with Daggett.
    - Dahlberg, Edward, 1937, 1968, 1977; 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Correspondence with Dahlberg; one article and one clipping.
    - Day, Mark, 1975-1979; 13 items. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Correspondence with Day, typed notes, and a clipping.
    - Dekker, Albert, 1968-1979; 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Letters concerning Dekker, one typed note, a manuscript by Dekker, and clippings.
    - di Giovanni, Norman Thomas, 1962-1967; 11 items. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Correspondence with di Giovanni; one article and one clipping.
    - Downey, Sheridan, 1933-1949; ca. 30 items. (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Letters regarding Downey, handwritten and typed notes, and assorted printed materials. Also includes correspondence with Downey and Stephen Downey.
    - Dreier, Mary, 1955-1961; 19 items. (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Correspondence with Dreier.
    - Eastlake, William, 1959, 1963, 1966-1971; 20 items. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      Correspondence with Eastlake; one black and white photograph of Eastlake, and some letters regarding his work.
    - Eaton, Cyrus, 1955-1979; 34 items. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Correspondence, primarily with Eaton; photocopy of a letter from Anna Louis Strong to Eaton, a press release, and clippings.
    - Ellsberg, Daniel, 1970; 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 15)
      Memoranda concerning a conversation in which Ellsberg discusses Henry Kissinger.
    - Elman, Richard, 1959-1979; 7 items. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Correspondence, primarily with Elman.
    - Erikson, Erik H., 1950, 1953; 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Letters from Erikson.
    - Fante, John (1 of 3), ca.1933-1960; 12 items. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      Contains correspondence (undated) with Fante, and clippings.
    - Fante, John (2 of 3), 1933-1948; 26 items. (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Correspondence with Fante, and a manuscript entitled "St. Anthony's Forty Wards." Also includes letters concerning "Home is the Hunter," by Fante and McWilliams.
    - Fante, John (3 of 3), 1951-1979; 45 items. (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Correspondence, primarily with Fante, but also with Marilyn Murphy-Pittman (regarding a biography she was writing on Fante) and Joyce Fante.
    - Feliz, Zoe Anne, 1974 June; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 21)
      A research paper by Feliz entitled "Carey McWilliams: A Selected Bibliography of His Works 1924-1954."
    - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1928-1980; 33 items. (Box 9, Folder 22)
      Correspondence with Flanner, and clippings of her publications.
    - Fleming, D.F., 1961-1962, 1968; 14 items. (Box 9, Folder 23)
      Correspondence with Fleming, and reviews.
    - Follett, Wilson, 1930-1966; 51 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Letters primarily from Wilson or Margaret Follett to Carey or Dorothy McWilliams. Clippings of published works by Follett.
    - Galvao, Henrique, 1960-1963, 1970, 1974; 67 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Letters, primarily regarding an article Galvao wrote for The Nation (including some correspondence between Galvao and McWilliams). Also contains clippings, press releases, two Galvao manuscripts in Portuguese, and The Seizing of the Santa Maria.
    - Gitt, J. W., 1948-1970; 31 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, primarily between Gitt and McWilliams, but also between Gitt and Freda Kirchwey or George Kirstein.
    - Glass, Murv Jr., 1974-1979; 17 items. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Correspondence with Glass, and photocopies of clippings.
    - Gottlieb, Bob, 1974-1976; 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with Gottlieb and Edward T. Chase.
    - Goulden, Joseph C., 1970-1971; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with Goulden.
    - Gruening, Ernest, 1964-1973; 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Correspondence with Gruening and George McGovern, and a clipping.
    - Halsell, Grace, 1977-1978; 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Correspondence with Halsell.
    - Haslam, Gerald, 1974-1978; 11 items. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Correspondence with Haslam.
    - Hilton, Ronald, 1960-1961, 1967; 22 items. (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Correspondence with Hilton; a press release and television program transcript, and clippings.
    - Hiss, Alger, 1978-1980; 42 items. (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Letters (including two from Hiss to McWilliams), clippings, articles, and book reviews.
    - Huling, Betty, 1968-1969; 8 items. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Correspondence concerning Huling.
    - Jeffers, Robinson, 1903-1935, 1962, 1973-1978; 19 items. (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Correspondence with Robinson and Uma Jeffers, and a letter from Jeffers to Louis Adamic. Also includes clippings, typed copies of poems by Jeffers, three copies of The Carmelite, and assorted printed materials.
    - Jones, Idwal, 1964, 1970; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 14)
      Clippings.
    - Josephson, Matthew, 1952-1953, 1960, 1967-1979; 43 items. (Box 10, Folder 15)
      Correspondence with Josephson, and letters from Hannah Josephson and David E. Shi. Manuscripts, including "The August 27 Attack on Radio and Book Publishing" by Josephson, and a chapter entitled "The Age of Darkness" by Shi. Clippings.
    - Julian, C.C., 1977; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Photocopy of article.
    - Kauffman, Joseph P., 1962-1964; 10 items. (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Correspondence concerning Kauffman, a television transcript, and a manuscript of a statement by The Nation's editors.
    - Kelley, Edith Summers, 1928-1940, 1972-1978; 31 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with Kelley, Matthew J. Bruccoli, and Jane Weisman Stein. Photocopies of letters, copies of poems by Kelley, and one clipping.
    - Kenny, Robert W., 1942-1979; 34 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Letters, including two from Kenny to McWilliams; clippings, and assorted printed materials.
    - Kerby, Phil, 1952, 1967-1970, 1976; 13 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Correspondence with Kerby; manuscript of a speech by Kerby.
    - King, Martin Luther, 1967, 1972; 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Correspondence with David E. Luellen, and an annotated manuscript of a February 1967 King speech given in Los Angeles at The Nation's conference on American foreign policy.
    - Kirchwey, Freda (1 of 3), 1948-1954; 19 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Correspondence between Kirchwey and McWilliams. Also includes letters from J.W. Gitt, and Dudley Nichols.
    - Kirchwey, Freda (2 of 3), 1972-1976; 18 items. (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Letters regarding Kirchwey, including correspondence with Sara Alpern in relation to her dissertation on Kirchwey.
    - Kirchwey, Freda (3 of 3), 1940-1949, 1976; ca. 60 items. (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Clippings, and assorted printed materials.
    - Kirstein, George and Lincoln, 1963-1978; 38 items. (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Correspondence between the Kirsteins and McWilliams. Also includes a typed note and clippings.
    - Lamb, Edward, 1951, 1976-1980; 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Letters from Lamb, a press release, and clippings.
    - Lamont, Corliss, 1955-1978; 29 items. (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Correspondence (primarily with Lamont), typewritten notes, clippings, and a manuscript by Lamont. One Basic Pamphlet by Lamont entitled My First Sixty Years, and assorted printed materials.
    - Lane, Mark, 1964-1970; 18 items. (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Letters regarding a manuscript by Lane rejected by The Nation. Also includes press releases and clippings.
    - Lasch, Christopher, 1967; 47 items. (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Correspondence, primarily with Lasch. Also includes one letter from Ralph Bunche to James Storrow, a partial clipping, and a handwritten note.
    - Lernoux, Penny, 1976-1980; 5 items. (Box 14, Folder 13)
      Letters from Lernoux to McWilliams.
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1962-1966; 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Correspondence with Lieber.
    - Lindsay, John V., 1961-1975; 11 items. (Box 14, Folder 15)
      Correspondence with Lindsay (primarily letters from Lindsay to McWilliams), a press release, and a clipping.
    - Love, Eulia (1 of 2), 1979-1980; 40 items. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Letters regarding Love, press releases, photocopies of clippings, and assorted printed materials.
    - Love, Eulia (2 of 2), 1979; ca. 40 items. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Newspaper clippings.
    - MacLeod, Leroy, 1929-1934, 1966; 14 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Letters from MacLeod.
    - MacLeod, Norman, 1931-1932; 7 items. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Correspondence with MacLeod.
    - Mandell, Maurice, 1955-1957; 3 items. (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with Mandell.
    - Mann, Abby, 1979; 2 items. (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Letter and a manuscript for The Sleepy Lagoon Murders.
    - Matthiessen, F.O., 1944-1950, 1973-1978; 8 items. (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Correspondence with Matthiessen, and clippings.
    - Matusow, Harvey, 1954-1960, 1968; 36 items. (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Letters regarding Matusow, clippings, a press release, and assorted printed materials.
    - McCann, Frasier, 1953-1979; 38 items. (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Letters (primarily from McWilliams to McCann), and a clipping.
    - McGovern, George, 1968-1979; 7 items. (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Correspondence with McGovern, primarily letters from him to McWilliams.
    - McGrath, Alice Greenfield, 1944-1945, 1953, 1970-1980; 31 items. (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Correspondence with McGrath. Includes letters regarding the Sleepy Lagoon case, one press release, one 3x5 color snapshot of McGrath in a small group, one copy of the Performing Arts playbill, clippings, and a manuscript of a statement by McWilliams for the Guy Endore pamphlet regarding the Sleepy Lagoon case.
    - McPherson, Aimee Semple (1 of 2), 1946-1947; 7 items. (Box 15, Folder 12)
      Letters regarding McPherson, typed notes, and a 30 page timeline/outline.
    - McPherson, Aimee Semple (2 of 2), 1929, 1978-1979; 4 items. (Box 15, Folder 13)
      A study by Gary Tavetian, and clippings.
    - Meiklejohn, Alexander, 1964-1965; 4 items. (Box 15, Folder 14)
      Correspondence with Alexander and Helen Meiklejohn, and clippings.
    - Mencken, H. L. (1 of 3), 1928-1941, 1955, 1977; 24 items. (Box 15, Folder 15)
      Letters, primarily from Mencken to McWilliams.
    - Mencken, H. L. (2 of 3), 1912, 1924-1934, 1965; 17 items. (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Clippings by and about Mencken. Also includes lecture notes by McWilliams, "Six Points About H.L. Mencken," and a McWilliams article "Notes on H. L. Mencken" from The Wooden Horse.
    - Mencken, H. L. (3 of 3), 1926-1931, 1971-1977; ca. 50 items. (Box 15, Folder 17)
      Newspaper clippings (mostly written by Mencken).
    - Mikulski, Marta, 1957-1973; 84 items. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with Mikulski, 12 black and white photographs of paintings done by Kazimierz Mikulski.
    - Mills, Omer, 1948; 4 items. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Correspondence concerning Mills, and McWilliams's Affidavit.
    - Monroe, Eason, 1951, 1974-1975; 6 items. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Correspondence with Monroe, photocopies, and a clipping.
    - Morse, Wayne, 1959, 1969-1973; 17 items. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Correspondence (primarily with Morse), and two press releases.
    - Mucha, Jiri, 1967-1969; 7 items. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Correspondence with Mucha.
    - Murrow, Edward R., 1955; 24 items. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with Murrow and Fred Friendly, typed statements by McWilliams in response to Anne Smart's request his work be banned, a transcript from the television show See It Now, and a clipping.
    - Navarro, Joseph (1 of 7), 1969-1970; 21 items. (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Correspondence, primarily with Navarro. Subjects include Navarro's review of North from Mexico, the reissue of North from Mexico, the founding of the Journal of Mexican American History, and a bibliography by Navarro and Ruben Cortez entitled Mexican-American History: A Critical Selective Bibliography. Also contains a review of aforementioned bibliography by McWilliams dated 1969 October 15.
    - Navarro, Joseph (2 of 7), 1971; 42 items. (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Correspondence, primarily with Navarro. Subjects include works relating to their common interests, Navarro's paper on McWilliams's contribution to the history of ethnic minorities, Navarro's studies, and funding for the Journal of Mexican American History. Also includes chronologies by McWilliams of his work/life.
    - Navarro, Joseph (3 of 7), 1972; 68 items. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      Correspondence primarily with Navarro. Subjects include Navarro's research for his dissertation on McWilliams, the article, "The Incarceration of the Japanese-Americans" by William Petersen, and a Guy T. Nunn letter with documents about McWilliams held by The National Archive. Also contains two letters from Alice Greenfield McGrath to McWilliams, 1 letter from McWilliams to William F. Buckley, Jr., correspondence with Kathleen O'Connor Navarro, a 10 page typed answer by McWilliams in response to Navarro's questions concerning his work/life, and the outline and abstract from Navarro's dissertation.
    - Navarro, Joseph (4 of 7), 1973; 31 items. (Box 20, Folder 10)
      Correspondence, primarily with Navarro, including a letter in which McWilliams discusses red-baiting. The primary subject is Navarro's research for his dissertation on McWilliams. Also contains correspondence with John Bright and William Petersen, a revised dissertation abstract and outline, as well as a copy of an article by McWilliams, "The Battle of Camp San Vicente."
    - Navarro, Joseph (5 of 7), 1974-1975; 43 items. (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, primarily with Navarro. Subjects include Navarro's research for his dissertation on McWilliams and the Journal of Mexican American History. Also contains correspondence with Kathleen O'Connor Navarro, and two manuscripts by Navarro from his dissertation (Chapter 2 and The Twenties).
    - Navarro, Joseph (6 of 7), 1976-1980; 20 items. (Box 20, Folder 12)
      Contains correspondence, primarily with Joseph and Kathleen O'Connor Navarro. Subjects include Navarro's research for his dissertation on McWilliams and the Journal of Mexican American History.
    - Navarro, Joseph (7 of 7), ca. 1970-1980; 3 items. (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Manuscripts: "Carey McWilliams as Minority Historian," "The Contribution of Carey McWilliams to Ethnic Historiography," and "Early Years and Rocky Mountain Background, 1905-1922."
    - Nelson, Patricia, 1974-1977; 9 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with Nelson.
    - Neruda, Pablo, 1964-1977; 33 items. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Clippings, and copies of Neruda's poems.
    - Neutra, Richard, 1948-1954, 1966-1979; 24 items. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Correspondence (with accompanying materials) primarily between Richard and Dione Neutra and McWilliams.
    - Nixon, Richard (1 of 6), 1969-1974; 38 items. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Memo, report, newsletters, press releases, clippings.
    - Nixon, Richard (2 of 6), 1969-1978; 31 items. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Nixon, Richard (3 of 6), 1970-1977; ca. 25 items. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Nixon, Richard (4 of 6), 1969-1977; ca. 50 items. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Nixon, Richard (5 of 6), 1969-1979; ca. 80 items. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Nixon, Richard (6 of 6), 1969-1977; ca. 80 items. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Noble, Robert, ca. 1950; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Leaflets.
    - Nossiter, Bernard, 1955-1957; 13 items. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Correspondence with Nossiter.
    - Orans, Alice, 1937-1947, 1954, 1970, 1979; ca. 20 items. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Assorted printed materials, primarily regarding either the Committee to Aid Agricultural Organization or the ACLU, including migrant labor ephemera. Also contains a letter from McWilliams to Sheridan Downey and a few letters from Alice and Martin Orans to McWilliams.
    - Packard, Walter, 1966-1977; 16 items. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Letters regarding Packard, including correspondence with Emma L. Packard. Also includes two manuscripts: a statement by McWilliams and an introduction by Alan Temko.
    - Pasternak, Boris, 1958, 1960; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Two letters, a handwritten note, and clippings regarding Pasternak winning the Nobel Prize.
    - Pauling, Linus, 1958-1960, 1975, 1977; 5 items. (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Two letters from Pauling to McWilliams, a handwritten note, and clippings.
    - Perry, Bernard, 1965, 1973-1977; 31 items. (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Correspondence with Perry, as well as related letters concerning a Nation anthology.
    - Phillips, Gifford, 1965-1971; 22 items. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Correspondence between Phillips and McWilliams, and a memo.